The Shah Research Collection M2042
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
the Shah Research Collection
circa 1921-2000
M2042
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
24.0 box(es)
An attempt to compile a complete copies of critical classified documents from British, American, French and few East German archieves relating to Iranian politics, economics, social and military developments circa 1921-2000. The documents include reports from embassies letters exhanged between governments, intelligence estimates presidential briefings, and minuets of high level meetings.
Milani, Abbas
Biographical/Historical Note
"Over the course of the last twenty five years, I have written three books on Muhammad Reza Shah's period--Persian Sphinx, Eminent Persians (2 Vols) and the Shah. The documents have been collected in the course of this period as primary source material for the research. I have traveled to these archives, read through their collections, and copied the most significant documents. On rare occasions, I have copied them from the Electronic Reading Rooms."
-Abbas Milani
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Arangement Note
Arranged in chronological order, by date of document.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Abbas Milani, 2014.
Milani, Abbas; Iran--Economic policy--20th century; Iran--Foreign relations; Iran--History--Mohammad Reza Pahlavi, 1919-1979; Iran--Kings and Rulers--biography; Iran--Military policy--History; Iran--Politics and Government, 1925-1979; Mohammad Reza Pahlavi, Shah of Iran, 1919-1980; Mohammad Reza Pahlavi, Shah of Iran, 1919-1980--Influence
- December 1919- April 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- May 1921- August 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- January 1925-October 1927 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 1933-1939 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- January 1940-May 1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- February 1941-October 1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- February 1942-December 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- January 1943-April 1943 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- May 1943-July 1943 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- August 1943-November 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- November 1943-December 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Reports-Declarations 1943 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- January 1944-March 1944 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- April 1944-July 1944 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- August 1944-Deceember 1944 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- January 1945-June 1945 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- January 1946-December 1946 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- January 1947-December 1947 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- February 1948- November 1948 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- January 1949- December 1949 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- January 1950- June 1950 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- July 1950-December 1950 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- January 1951- November 1951 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- January 1952-Decmber 1952 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- January 1953- May 1953 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- June 1953- August 1953 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- August 1953-December 1953 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- January 1954- December 1954 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- January 1955- May 1955 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- June 1955- December 1955 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- January 1956-December 1956 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- January 1957- December 1957 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- January 1958-December 1958 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- January 1959-December 1959 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- January 1960-May 1960 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- June 1960-Deecember 1960 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- January 1961-February 1961 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- March 1961-April 1961 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- April 1961- May 1961 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- May 1961- (Box 7, Folder 4)
- June 1961-August 1961 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- September 1961- November 1961 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- November 1961-December 1961 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- January 1962-March 1962 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- April 1962 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- May 1962 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- June 1962-July 1962 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- August 1962-December 1962 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- January 1963- May 1963 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- June 1963-July 1963 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- August 1963-December 1963 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- January 1964-May 1964 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- June 1964-December 1964 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- January 1965-February 1965 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- March 1965-December 1965 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- January 1966-April 1966 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- May 1966-December 1966 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- January 1967- December 1967 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- January 1968- March 1968 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- April 1968- June 1968 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- July 1968-September 1968 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- October 1968- November 1968 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- December 1968 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- January 1969- December 1969 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- January 1970-December 1970 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- January 1971-April 1971 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- May 1971-Deecember 1971 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- January 1972-December 1972 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- January 1973-March 1973 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- April 1973-July 1973 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- August 1973-December 1973 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- January 1974-December 1974 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- January 1975-December 1975 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- January 1976-April 1976 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- May 1976-December 1976 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- January 1977-December 1977 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- January 1978-May 1978 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- June 1978-September 1978 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- October 1978 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- November 1978 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- December 1978 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Report 1974-1978 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- January 1979 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- January 1979 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- February-April 1979 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- May 1979-September 1079 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- October 1979 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- November 1979-December 1979 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- January 1980-December 1980 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- January 1981-December 1981 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- 1984 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- 1985 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- 1986 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- 1987 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- 1988 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Unknown date (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Unknown date (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Unknown date (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Unknown date (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Wikileaks 2003-2006 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Wikileaks 2007 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Wikileaks 2008 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Wikileaks 2009 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Wikileaks 2010 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- German archives (Box 17, Folder 1)
- German archives (Box 17, Folder 2)
- German archives (Box 17, Folder 3)
- German archives (Box 17, Folder 4)
- German archives (Box 17, Folder 5)
- rench archives (1951) (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Dr. Milani's articles (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Dr. Milani's articles (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Dr. Milani's articles (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Dr. Milani's articles (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Various diplomatic papers (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Various diplomatic papers (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Various papers -reports (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Oversize papers 1941 (Othertype 21, Folder 1)
- Oversize papers 1942 (Othertype 21, Folder 2)
- Oversize papers 1943-1964 (Othertype 21, Folder 3)
- Oversize papers 1965-1968 (Othertype 21, Folder 4)
- Oversize papers 1969-1970 (Othertype 21, Folder 5)
- Oversize papers 1971 (Othertype 22, Folder 1)
- Oversize papers 1972 (Othertype 22, Folder 2)
- Oversize papers 1973 (Othertype 22, Folder 3)
- Oversize papers 1974 (Othertype 22, Folder 4)
- Oversize papers 1975 (Othertype 22, Folder 5)
- Oversize papers 1976-1977 (Othertype 23, Folder 1)
- Oversize papers 1978 (Othertype 23, Folder 2)
- Oversize papers 1979 (Othertype 23, Folder 3)
- Unknown date (Othertype 23, Folder 4)
- Newspaper Articles 2005-2009 (Othertype 24)